<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Homebrew Weapons</name>
        <description></description>
        <author ulr="">FredSullz</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FredSullz/homebrew/main/items-weapons.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Kazimir's Dagger of Hatred" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_HOMEBREW_KAZIMIRS_DAGGER_OF_HATRED">
        <description>
            <p>A beautiful obsidian dagger with a dark red opal embedded in the hilt. The opal glows faintly red when attuned.</p>
            <p>You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon</p>
            <p>While attuned, you gain certain bonuses while attacking enemies of a different race than your own with this weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">You have advantage on attack rolls.</p>
            <p class="indent">You deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a critical hit, the target must succeed on a constitution saving throw or be petrified for an hour.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are a Dhampir, an attack roll of 25 or higher (after bonuses) is considered a crit.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong>While attuned, a slow hatred will build towards any humanoid creature of another race that you spend a prolonged time with. Every 24 hours make a wisdom saving throw (DC 18) or increase your hatred by one step towards that creature. For each step the opal glows slightly stronger.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">dagger, curse</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
            <set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
            <set name="name-format">Kazimir's Dagger of Hatred</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blade of the Seraph" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_HOMEBREW_SERAPH_BLADE">
        <description>
            <p>A blade forged from celestial steel, granted only to a select few, who had been chosen to hunt any fiend who sets foot on the material plane. These chosen have long been thought extinct, though their blades, untouched by time, still remain where such a being might have fallen. It is unknown what creatures wielded these blades, though many speculate the Aasimar might be descendants of the original chosen. The design of the blade varies greatly, with the most common ones being shortswords.</p>
            <p>You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
            <p>While attuned, attacks made with this weapon deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage while attacking a fiend.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">sword</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="enhancement">1</set>
            <set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
            <set name="name-format">Blade of the Seraph</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>